[
    {
        "question": "What does XML stand for?",
        "options": [
            "eXtensible Markup Language",
            "eXtra Multi-Program Language",
            "eXecutable Multiple Language",
            "eXtra Modern Link"
        ],
        "answer": "eXtensible Markup Language"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true about XML?",
        "options": [
            "XML is designed to transport and store data.",
            "XML is designed to display data.",
            "XML is a replacement for HTML.",
            "XML can be used to create animations."
        ],
        "answer": "XML is designed to transport and store data."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a correct XML tag?",
        "options": [
            "<note>",
            "<_note>",
            "<note123>",
            "<Note>"
        ],
        "answer": "<_note>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a correct way of declaring an XML namespace?",
        "options": [
            "<note xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\">",
            "<note xml=\"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\">",
            "<note ns=\"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\">",
            "<note namespace=\"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\">"
        ],
        "answer": "<note xmlns=\"http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml\">"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about XML?",
        "options": [
            "XML tags are case sensitive.",
            "All XML elements must be properly closed.",
            "XML tags are predefined.",
            "XML documents must have a root element."
        ],
        "answer": "XML tags are predefined."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct XML declaration?",
        "options": [
            "<?xml version=\"1.0\" encoding=\"UTF-8\"?>",
            "<xml version=\"1.0\" encoding=\"UTF-8\">",
            "<xml version=\"1.0\"?>",
            "<?xml version=\"1.0\"?>"
        ],
        "answer": "<?xml version=\"1.0\" encoding=\"UTF-8\"?>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the root element of this XML document?\n<root>\n  <child>value</child>\n</root>",
        "options": [
            "<root>",
            "<child>",
            "value",
            "root"
        ],
        "answer": "<root>"
    },
    {
        "question": "How do you define an attribute in an XML element?",
        "options": [
            "<element attribute=\"value\">",
            "<element.attribute='value'>",
            "<element:attribute='value'>",
            "<element>attribute='value'</element>"
        ],
        "answer": "<element attribute=\"value\">"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a well-formed XML document?",
        "options": [
            "<note><to>Tove</to><from>Jani</from></note>",
            "<note><to>Tove</from></note>",
            "<note><to>Tove<from>Jani</from></note>",
            "<note><to>Tove><from>Jani</from></note>"
        ],
        "answer": "<note><to>Tove</to><from>Jani</from></note>"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does CDATA stand for in XML?",
        "options": [
            "Character Data",
            "Custom Data",
            "Content Data",
            "Control Data"
        ],
        "answer": "Character Data"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid XML data type?",
        "options": [
            "string",
            "int",
            "float",
            "array"
        ],
        "answer": "array"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of a DTD in XML?",
        "options": [
            "To define the structure and the legal elements and attributes of an XML document.",
            "To display the data in a web browser.",
            "To style the XML document.",
            "To transform the XML document into another format."
        ],
        "answer": "To define the structure and the legal elements and attributes of an XML document."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a type of XML parser?",
        "options": [
            "DOM",
            "SAX",
            "StAX",
            "HTML"
        ],
        "answer": "HTML"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true about XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "XML Schema defines the structure of an XML document.",
            "XML Schema is a subset of DTD.",
            "XML Schema is used to style XML documents.",
            "XML Schema is used to convert XML documents into other formats."
        ],
        "answer": "XML Schema defines the structure of an XML document."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a correct way to define a comment in XML?",
        "options": [
            "<!-- This is a comment -->",
            "<! This is a comment !>",
            "<comment>This is a comment</comment>",
            "// This is a comment"
        ],
        "answer": "<!-- This is a comment -->"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid XML name?",
        "options": [
            "note",
            "note1",
            "1note",
            "note_1"
        ],
        "answer": "1note"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of an XML namespace?",
        "options": [
            "To avoid name conflicts in XML documents.",
            "To style the XML document.",
            "To transform XML documents.",
            "To display XML documents in web browsers."
        ],
        "answer": "To avoid name conflicts in XML documents."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about XML attributes?",
        "options": [
            "Attributes provide additional information about elements.",
            "Attributes must always be quoted.",
            "Attributes can be used to define complex data structures.",
            "Attributes are case-sensitive."
        ],
        "answer": "Attributes can be used to define complex data structures."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define the order of elements in an XML document?",
        "options": [
            "Sequence",
            "Choice",
            "All",
            "Group"
        ],
        "answer": "Sequence"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is XSLT in XML?",
        "options": [
            "A language for transforming XML documents.",
            "A schema definition language.",
            "A parser for XML documents.",
            "A language for querying XML documents."
        ],
        "answer": "A language for transforming XML documents."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to select nodes from an XML document?",
        "options": [
            "XPath",
            "XQuery",
            "XSLT",
            "XLink"
        ],
        "answer": "XPath"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the role of an XML namespace prefix?",
        "options": [
            "To distinguish elements and attributes with the same name.",
            "To define the data type of an element.",
            "To style the XML document.",
            "To transform XML documents."
        ],
        "answer": "To distinguish elements and attributes with the same name."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a part of the XML document structure?",
        "options": [
            "DTD",
            "CSS",
            "Schema",
            "Element"
        ],
        "answer": "CSS"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to link XML documents?",
        "options": [
            "XLink",
            "XPath",
            "XQuery",
            "XSLT"
        ],
        "answer": "XLink"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to query XML documents?",
        "options": [
            "XQuery",
            "XPath",
            "XSLT",
            "XLink"
        ],
        "answer": "XQuery"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid XML processing instruction?",
        "options": [
            "<?xml-stylesheet type=\"text/xsl\" href=\"style.xsl\"?>",
            "<?xml:stylesheet type=\"text/xsl\" href=\"style.xsl\"?>",
            "<?stylesheet type=\"text/xsl\" href=\"style.xsl\"?>",
            "<?xml-stylesheet type=\"text/css\" href=\"style.css\"?>"
        ],
        "answer": "<?xml-stylesheet type=\"text/xsl\" href=\"style.xsl\"?>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true about XML elements?",
        "options": [
            "XML elements can have child elements.",
            "XML elements cannot contain attributes.",
            "XML elements must always be empty.",
            "XML elements cannot contain text."
        ],
        "answer": "XML elements can have child elements."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is true about XML DTD?",
        "options": [
            "DTD defines the structure of an XML document.",
            "DTD can be used to validate XML documents.",
            "DTD is written in XML.",
            "DTD can be used to transform XML documents."
        ],
        "answer": "DTD defines the structure of an XML document."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid way to define an XML comment?",
        "options": [
            "<!-- This is a comment -->",
            "<comment>This is a comment</comment>",
            "<! This is a comment !>",
            "// This is a comment"
        ],
        "answer": "<!-- This is a comment -->"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does XML Schema use to define the structure of an XML document?",
        "options": [
            "XSD",
            "DTD",
            "HTML",
            "CSS"
        ],
        "answer": "XSD"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define complex types in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:complexType>",
            "<xs:simpleType>",
            "<xs:type>",
            "<xs:element>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:complexType>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define simple types in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:simpleType>",
            "<xs:complexType>",
            "<xs:type>",
            "<xs:element>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:simpleType>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid XML Schema data type?",
        "options": [
            "integer",
            "string",
            "float",
            "list"
        ],
        "answer": "list"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a list of acceptable values in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:enumeration>",
            "<xs:choice>",
            "<xs:list>",
            "<xs:sequence>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:enumeration>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid XML Schema facet?",
        "options": [
            "pattern",
            "length",
            "minInclusive",
            "format"
        ],
        "answer": "format"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a required element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "minOccurs",
            "maxOccurs",
            "required",
            "occurs"
        ],
        "answer": "minOccurs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define an optional element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "minOccurs=\"0\"",
            "maxOccurs=\"0\"",
            "optional=\"true\"",
            "occurs=\"optional\""
        ],
        "answer": "minOccurs=\"0\""
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a repeating element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "maxOccurs",
            "minOccurs",
            "repeats",
            "repeat"
        ],
        "answer": "maxOccurs"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a unique element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:unique>",
            "<xs:key>",
            "<xs:id>",
            "<xs:distinct>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:unique>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a reference to another element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:keyref>",
            "<xs:reference>",
            "<xs:ref>",
            "<xs:key>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:keyref>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define an attribute in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:attribute>",
            "<xs:element>",
            "<xs:attr>",
            "<xs:field>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:attribute>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a group of elements in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:group>",
            "<xs:sequence>",
            "<xs:choice>",
            "<xs:all>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:group>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a sequence of elements in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:sequence>",
            "<xs:group>",
            "<xs:choice>",
            "<xs:all>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:sequence>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a choice of elements in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:choice>",
            "<xs:sequence>",
            "<xs:group>",
            "<xs:all>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:choice>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define an unordered group of elements in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "<xs:all>",
            "<xs:sequence>",
            "<xs:group>",
            "<xs:choice>"
        ],
        "answer": "<xs:all>"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a default value for an element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "default",
            "fixed",
            "value",
            "defaultValue"
        ],
        "answer": "default"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a fixed value for an element in XML Schema?",
        "options": [
            "fixed",
            "default",
            "value",
            "fixedValue"
        ],
        "answer": "fixed"
    }
  ]
